(マダラ)赤い蒸気。
Red vapor...
八門全開時 特有の
血の蒸気というやつか。
The unique vapor of blood
from the opening of
all eight gates.
フフ だが こうやって見ると
何だろうな。
But actually seeing it
with my own eyes,
まるで秋に散り朽ちる
枯れ葉色 落ち葉のようよ。
it's almost like the color of
dead autumn leaves
that have fallen off their tree.
(ガイ)確かに そうだ。
You're right.
だが ただ朽ちて
落ちるわけではない。
But they're not falling
without reason or purpose.
それは 新たな
青葉の養分となるのだ。
They become the nutrients...
for fresh green leaves!
そして 青葉が芽吹く
新たな春へと繋げるときこそが→
And the period they bridge,
until the new spring when
fresh leaves bud...
青春の最高潮！
真紅に燃えるとき！
is the climax of youth!
When it burns most crimson!
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Eight Inner Gates Formation
壱足！
First Step!
Go for it, Guy Sensei!
(リー)行ってください ガイ先生！
僕は もう…。
I can...
no longer...
うぉ～っ！
ぐっ！
(ミナト)ガイ それが キミの…。
Guy, is that your—?!
あれが ガイ先生の言っていた夕象！
That is Sensei's Sekizo,
the Evening Elephant!
(ガイ)弐足！
Second Step!
うぅ！
途中で止めた!?
He stopped midway?!
《夕象は １速から５速までの
ギア上げ連続攻撃のはず》
The Evening Elephant is supposed
to be a continuous attack
that can be shifted up in speed
from one to five times...
《なるほど とてつもない痛みだ。
I see, what unbelievable pain.
だが もう慣れた。
But I've acclimated.
次こそ連続 隙は与えない！》
Next time, I can keep it going without
giving him any openings.
《八門の杜門まででも
相当な負荷を体に強いる。
Great stress is placed on
the body even through
the Fifth Gate, the Gate of Closing...
おそらく死門の痛みは
僕の想像を絶するもののはず！》
I bet the Gate of Death's
level of pain
is something that exceeds
my imagination!
空気を殴りつけ
ぶつけてくる体術技か。
A taijutsu move that bombards
with blows of punched air...
いわゆる空気砲。
An air cannon, so to speak...
《あれを４～５発
くらい続ければ やっかいだな。
Taking four or five of those
would be bad.
何より それを作り出す拳に→
I should definitely avoid getting hit
by the fists creating them too.
直接やられるのは
避けたほうがいいだろう》
(カカシ)やったか？
Did he succeed?!
八門遁甲の陣とやり合うのは稀だ。
One rarely gets to fight
the Eight Inner Gates Formation!
I'm game! I'll play with you!
せっかくだ 相手をしてやる。
I figured as much...
He didn't bring him down yet.
やはり まだ 倒せはしないか。
(我愛羅)マイト・ガイは何をした？
What has Might Guy done?
八門遁甲の陣。
己の力のリミッターを外し→
The Eight Inner Gates Formation...
A technique that allows one to
draw out their maximum power
極限まで 力を引き出す技だよ。
by releasing the limiters
placed on it.
(カカシ)かつて 中忍試験で
リー君が キミにやってみせた→
It's the final stage of the jutsu
Lee used against you
in the Chunin Exams long ago.
あれの最終段階。
リミッターの全開放は→
Releasing all eight limiters results
in power tens of times greater
五影をも上回る 何十倍もの
力を出すことができる。
than that of the Five Kage.
だが それは いっとき。
この技のあと 開放者は…。
But it's only temporary.
After using this technique,
the user will...
必ず死ぬ。
inevitably die.
空中を蹴り上がってくるとはな。
He's coming towards me
by kicking air!
((コイツは 愛すべき
俺の大切な部下だ！))
He is...
my precious student whom I love.
リー お前…。
Lee, are you—?
悲しくなんかありません！
I am not sad!
覚悟を決めた男を前に→
Showing any pity or sorrow
to someone
哀れみも 悲しみも
侮辱になります！
who has resolved himself
would be an insult!
俺たちは ガイのサポートだ 聞いてくれ。
We must assist Guy.
Listen up.
(カカシ)先生 ヤツの あの黒い武器が
やっかいですが…。
Sensei...
Those black weapons of his
are troublesome...
発動型ではなく 形態変化をする
消えない常備タイプ。
They're not the activating-from
-nothing type,
but an always-on-standby
type that undergo Change in Form.
触れた箇所は消える。
が 接触した感覚がハッキリとある。
Their impact points disappear,
but there is clear sensation
if they make contact with you.
そして あれを飛ばせる
距離は約70メートル。
Also, he can only send them
about 70 meters out.
それ以上は
コントロールがきかなくなるからだ。
Any further than that,
and he'll lose control over them.
ちゃんと存在し
目視して追えるなら→
Since they actually exist and
can be seen with the eye,
キミの神威も通じる ということ。
your Kamui should work on them.
そして マダラから離してしまえば
コントロールを失わせられる。
By sending them away,
we can prevent Madara from
controlling them.
正直 言って 左目は
見えなくなってきてまして。
To be honest, I'm beginning
to lose sight in my left eye.
神威で的確に狙うには
かなり近づかないと。
I'll have to get pretty close to
target my Kamui accurately.
我愛羅君 砂を準備してくれる？
Gaara, can you prepare some sand?
俺の砂で カカシを
上空へってことだろうが→
You want me to transport Kakashi
with my sand, right?
俺の砂のスピードでは
ヤツの攻撃の的になるぞ？
But my sand isn't fast enough
to avoid his attacks.
大丈夫。 俺がいるから。
Don't worry.
That's where I come in.
カカシには 俺のクナイを持たせる。
I'll have Kakashi carry
one of my kunai.
(リー)八門遁甲 第六景門！ 開!!
Eight Inner Gates:
The Sixth Gate of Joy!
Open!
リー君！ キミも八門を？
Lee!
You've mastered
the Eight Inner Gates too?!
僕は 六門までしか開けません。
I can only open up to
the Sixth Gate...
今ほど 自分の力のなさを
呪ったことはありません！
I've never cursed my own lack
of power as I do now!
いや それでいいんだよ リー君。
No... That's enough, Lee.
だって キミは まだ…。
Because you're still...
... a fresh new leaf Guy wants
to risk his life to protect!
ガイが命をかけて守りたい
青葉なんだから。
リー君。 キミは ここで
我愛羅君のサポートと護衛をお願い。
Lee, I want you to stay here
to support and guard Gaara.
それと もう一つ。 僕のクナイを。
And one more thing...
Take one of my kunai.
(ガイ)壱足！
First Step!
He is fast!
やはり速い。
(ガイ)弐足！
Second Step!
参足！ 肆足！
Third Step!
Fourth Step!
《ぐはっ！ 動けぬ…》
I can't move!
伍促！
Fifth Step!
Just keep forging on, Guy!
No matter what!
何があろうと ただ突っ込め ガイ!!
《来るか？》
Here he comes!
うお～っ！
《いいタイミングだ リー君！》
Great timing, Lee!
神威！
Kamui!
ぐはっ！
ハァ… ハァ…。
ハァ ハァ…。
あっ！
柱間以来だ このワクワクは。
You're the first since Hashirama
to make me feel this excited!
まだ踊れるだろう？
Can you still dance?
更に別の技はないのか？
もっと楽しませてくれ！
Do you have any
other techniques?
Give me some more fun!
《コイツ 連続の夕象を…》
He got up from a barrage of Sekizo?
(ナルト)あっ！
ここは…。
Where am I?
Did I die?
俺ってば 死んだのか？
(ハゴロモ)何をもって死とする？
What makes thee think
that thou art dead?
おぬしの死に対する倫理的観点は
わしの時代のものとは異なるな。
Thine ethical viewpoint
on death differs much
from that which prevailed
in my time...
簡単に己を死という言葉に
置き換えるとは…。
To so easily replace oneself
with the term "death"...
気概を持つのだ 新人よ。
Thou must gain mettle,
oh fledgling.
誰？
Who are you?
(ハゴロモ)ここにおいて
的確な質問ではあるが→
'Tis quite a precise query
for this place, but...
わしの名を聞き
先駆者の見聞と一致するかは→
I am quite uneasy over
whether thou shalt be able
to connect my name with
my actions as a herald...
いささか不安ではある。
I am he who shall achieve
peace and order...
(ハゴロモ)我は 安寧秩序を成す者
名をハゴロモという。
My name is Hagoromo.
On the other hand...
その返し… こちらとしても
そのような状態になる兆しは→
I had foreseen
that thou wouldst end up
in such a state as that.
読み取っておったわ。
《なんか
何言ってっか よくわかんねえ…。
Uh... I don't understand
what the hell he's saying.
いるんだよなぁ。
He seems to be one of
those annoying geezers!
こういう うっとうしいタイプの
じじいって…》
じいちゃん 悪いんだけど 俺さ…。
Hey, gramps, sorry.
But, I...
さて…。
あっ その眼！
Now then...
Hey! Those eyes!
輪廻眼！
Rinnegan!
人を観察する眼は
持っておるようだな。
Thou dost appear to
possess observant eyes.
あとは 己の この状況を
現実的に理解できるとよいが…。
All that remains is for thee
to pragmatically comprehend
thy circumstances.
おぬしは
まだ死んだわけではない。
Thou hast not died yet...
ここは おぬしの精神世界だ。
はやる気持は わかるが…。
This place is thine inner mind.
I understand thine haste,
– This geezer's not an enemy?
– but at this moment,
《このじいちゃん
敵じゃねえのか？ でも…》
– This geezer's not an enemy?
– rushing will accomplish naught.
But...
もっと スムーズに 簡単に
普通に話せねえのかよ！
Can't you speak a little more smoothly,
using easy, normal words?
I am an anachronism.
わしは 時代錯誤である。
長きにわたる時の流れは
文化的伝統や観念 倫理において→
Over the passage of much time,
cultural traditions and
notions, and ethics
have brought about
significant change.
大きな変化をもたらしたのだ。
こうして時代をこえ
転生者に会うたびに→
Each occurrence where I cross
time and meet a reincarnate,
それらの両者にある相違を
大きく感じることとなった。
I have come to sense
greatly the differences
between the other and myself...
新たな文化や言語を形式主義的に
規定し学ぶことも…。
I was also able to
formalistically regulate and
learn new mores and words, however...
だ～っ！ うっせえよ もう！
Shut up already!
俺ってば こんなところで→
I don't have the time
to be sitting around
変なじじいの話 聞いてる場合じゃ
ねえっての！
and listening to
some weird geezer!
言葉の探求 一般学問全般とは
あいまいなものであり→
Not just searching for words...
But there is ambiguity
in scholarship.
定義困難ではあるがゆえに
意思の疎通ができぬとあらば→
If communication of wills
cannot be achieved
in addition to difficulty of definition...
今の観念論的な上学と
唯物論的な考えを考慮して→
I see that I must speak simply...
taking into account current idealistic
and materialistic thinking.
簡単に話してみるしか…。
Are you an alien or something?
アンタ 宇宙人か 何かか？
威厳はメッチャあるように感じっけど。
I mean, you seem
super dignified, but...
つうか それ言いすぎじゃね？
宇宙人って なんだよ ハハハッ…。
Uh, that's a bit much, doncha think?
An alien? Seriously?
えっ？
つって あんま違わねえか。
Well, maybe that ain't too far off.
So anyway...
それと… ん？
まだ伝わらぬか。 これほど会話が
複雑な様相を呈している…。
Do you still fail to understand me?
To think that conversation would
pose such a complex challenge...
No! Keep talking like just now.
I finally get you!
あ いやいや…。
さっきのしゃべりでいいから。
やっとわかったから。
ただ しゃべり方が
あまりにもシフトしすぎて→
I was just shocked because
your speaking style
changed so drastically, ya know?
びっくりしただけだってばよ。
Oh, for real?
あ マジ？ なら こんな感じで
いくんでよろしく つって。
Then I'll keep going like this.
Much pleased!
あ～ でも なんか しゃべりと
顔がまったく一致しねえから→
Uh, yeah.
Oh but, those words don't match up
with your face at all,
すげえ 怖ぇんだよね。
so it's kind of super-scary...
And he loses all dignity too.
《威厳が まったくなくなるし…》
やっぱ もうちょい
かたい感じ残しつつ…。
You should be just a bit more formal.
急に バカみたくなるから。
Otherwise, you come off
kind of dumb.
それは 言いすぎではないか。
バカとは何ごとだ！
Now you're going too far, no?
What do you mean by dumb?!
Well, considering how
I was talking before,
まぁ さっきのしゃべりでは
そう思われても しかたないか…。
I guess I can't blame you for that.
と こんな感じは どうだ？
So how's this then?
はい そこ！ オッケー！
そこで決めて！
That's it! All right!
That's perfect!
Indeed. I'm getting
the hang of it too.
うむ… だいたい わかってきたぞ。
ハァ…
やっと会話ができるってばよ。
Finally, I can talk with you.
ところで じいちゃんは何もん？
So anyway, gramps, who are you?
ここのこと詳しいんだったらさ→
If you know a lot about this place,
どうやって出ればいいか
教えてほしいんだけど。
tell me how to
get out of here!
質問を いっぺんにするな。
Don't ask so many questions
all at once!
わしは
すでに死んでいる昔の者だ。
I am a person of the past,
someone long dead.
チャクラだけで この世を漂い→
A monk who wanders through
this world as chakra,
crossing generations, ascertaining
the course of Ninshu, the Ninja Creed.
世代をこえて忍宗の行く末を
見届けてきた僧侶。
名を ハゴロモ。
そして忍宗の開祖にして→
My name is Hagoromo,
the founder of the Ninja Creed.
I'm also known as
the Sage of Six Paths.
六道仙人ともいう。
えっ 六道仙人!?
What?! The Sage of Six Paths?!
エロ仙人と長門が言ってた…
昔話のあの 仙人!?
The sage from the legends that
Pervy Sage and Nagato talked about?
ほう 知っておったか。
Oh, so you know about me?
知ってるも何も…。
最初に忍術を作った人だろ？
Of course I do!
You're the one who
created ninjutsu, right?
忍術ではなく忍宗だ。
Not ninjutsu...
Ninshu, the Ninja Creed.
わしの忍宗は
希望を作り出すためのものだった。
My Ninja Creed was something
meant to birth hope.
Do not confuse it with ninjutsu
which breeds conflict!
戦いを作り出す忍術と
混同してはいかん！
ああ とにかく…
アンタが仙人なら→
In any case, if you're the sage,
聞きたいことが
いっぱいあんだけど。
I've got tons of things
I wanna ask you.
でも 今は…。
But first, right now...
お前は我が息子 アシュラの…。
You are my son Ashura's...
とにかく今は
いろいろと条件が整ったのだ。
Anyway, the conditions are
all in place now.
There are things I must
entrust you with.
わしは お前に託さなければ
ならないことがある。
アシュラ？ たくす？
Ashu... ra? Entrust?
ワケわかんねえこと言ってねえで
俺を こっから出してくれって！
Quit talking gibberish and
let me out of here!
すまんが それは わしに
どうこうできる話ではない。
Forgive me... That is something I have
no influence over.
外の者が お前をどうするかだ。
That depends on the actions
of those outside.
わしは お前に伝えるだけだ。
I can only relay things to you.
また 何言ってっか
わかんなくなってきたってばよ。
I'm not getting what
you're saying again!
とにかく 今は お前が慌てても
しようがないということだ。
It means right now,
trying to rush won't make
any difference.
なので 少し聞いてもらおう。
So I want you to listen for a bit...
いや お前は聞かねばならない。
No, you must listen...
まずは
わしの母と息子たちについて。
First, about my mother and sons.
(ハゴロモ)わしの母である
大筒木カグヤは→
My mother, Kaguya Otsutsuki,
遠い場所から
お前たちの この地に来た。
came to this land of yours
from a faraway place.
神樹の実をとりに来たのだ。
She came in search of
the fruit of the Divine Tree.
お前たちも この戦争で見た
あの神樹。
The chakra fruit of
that same Divine Tree,
そのチャクラの実だ。
that you have seen in this war.
カグヤは その実を喰らい→
Kaguya consumed
the fruit, attained power,
力を得て この地を治めた。
and subdued this land.
カグヤって どっから来たの？
Where'd Kaguya come from?
六道仙人より強い？
Is she stronger than you,
Sage of Six Paths?
やっぱ 母ちゃんって
怒ると怖ぇもんね。
I guess all moms are scary
when they're mad, huh?
どこから来たかは
どうでもいいことだ。
It matters not where
she came from.
母は強かった 誰よりも。
Mother was powerful...
More powerful than any other.
人々は母を卯の女神だの
鬼だのと呼び→
Some called my mother
the Rabbit Goddess
and others considered her
a demon...
崇め 恐れていた。
They both worshipped her
and feared her.
のちに カグヤは２人の子供を産んだ。
Later, Kaguya would birth two sons.
そのうちの一人が わしだ。
I was one of them.
わしら兄弟は
母の残した罪をあがなうため→
We brothers, to atone for
the crimes mother left behind,
神樹の化身たる十尾と戦い→
battled Ten Tails, an incarnation
of the Divine Tree,
それを己に封印した。
and sealed it inside me.
チャクラの実をとられた神樹は→
The Divine Tree,
robbed of its Chakra Fruit,
それを取り返そうとして
暴れていたのだ。
went on a rampage in
an attempt to recover it.
それから更にのち
わしも２人の子供を授かった。
Much, much later,
I had two sons of my own.
兄をインドラ 弟をアシュラと名づけ→
I named the elder, Indra,
and the younger, Ashura,
忍宗を教えたのだ。
and I taught them
the Ninja Creed.
だが２人には大きな差があった。
But there was a huge difference
between the two.
わしの強いチャクラを持つ遺伝子と
そうでもない遺伝子。
One possessed genes containing
my powerful chakra
and the other did not.
その伝承が極端に出現したのだ。
And this difference manifested
itself in an extreme manner.
また難しくなってきてるってばよ。
It's getting complicated again,
ya know?
つまり どういうこと？
What does this all mean?
つまり 優秀な兄 インドラと→
In short...
There was the exceptional
older brother, Indra...
落ちこぼれの弟 アシュラ。
and the dunce
younger brother, Ashura.
落ちこぼれねぇ…。
A dunce, huh?
親が六道仙人だってのに。
Even though his dad's
the Sage of Six Paths?
これは言うべきでは
ないかもしれんが→
Perhaps there's no need
to say this to you, but...
両親がいくら優秀とて→
No matter how exceptional
both parents may be,
その力をそのまま
受け継ぐとはかぎらん。
there's no guarantee one will
inherit outright either of their abilities.
心当たりがあろう。
Sound familiar?
お前も そうだったようだからな
ナルトよ。
Just as it seems to have been
in your case, Naruto.
なんとなく わかったってばよ。
For some reason,
I understand that completely.
お前は本当に
アシュラとよく似ている。
And you are truly similar
to Ashura, in your actions as well.
やってきたことも。
えっ やってきたこと？
Huh? My actions?
インドラとアシュラは違う道を歩いた。
Indra and Ashura walked
different paths in life.
兄 インドラは 生まれしときより→
Elder brother, Indra, possessed
strong Visual Prowess
強い瞳力とセンスをあわせもち
天才と呼ばれた。
and senses from birth,
and was called a genius.
何でも１人の力でやりぬき→
He always did everything alone,
leaning only on his own strength
己の力が他人とは違う
特別なものだと知った。
and came to understand that his powers
were different and special.
力こそがすべてを
可能にすると悟った。
He perceived that power could
achieve everything.
一方 弟のアシュラは→
On the other hand, nothing ever went well
for the younger brother, Ashura,
小さい頃から何をやっても
うまくいかず→
from the time he was young.
１人では何もできなかった。
And he couldn't do anything
on his own.
兄と同じ力を得るためには→
In order to attain the same power
as his older brother,
己の努力と 他人の協力を
必要とせざるを得なかった。
he needed the cooperation of others
in addition to his own effort.
アシュラは 修業の苦しみの中で
肉体のチャクラが開花し→
While struggling through training,
the power of bodily chakra awakened
within Ashura
兄と並ぶ力を得た。
and he attained power
rivaling his brother's.
強くなれたのは 皆の協力や
助けがあったからこそだと→
He came to understand that
he was able to become strong,
thanks to the cooperation and
help of those around him.
理解したのだ。
(ハゴロモ)そこには 他人を思いやる
愛があることを知った。
He learned of the love for others that
arises from thinking about others...
愛こそが すべてを
可能にすると悟ったのだ。
And perceived that it was love
that can achieve everything.
わしは 弟アシュラの生き方の中に→
In the way that the younger one
chose to live his life...
新たな可能性を
かいま見た気がした。
I thought I caught a glimpse
of new possibilities.
そして 己の中の十尾の力を分散し
個々に名を与え→
I partitioned the power of
the Ten Tails inside of me,
and named each of the pieces...
協力という繋がりこそ
本当の力だと信じたのだ。
And believed that the bond known
as "cooperation" was true power.
そこで わしは 弟アシュラを→
I then named
the younger brother, Ashura,
皆を導く 忍宗の後見人とした。
the leader and guardian
of the Ninja Creed,
兄インドラも 弟に→
believing that his elder brother, Indra,
would cooperate with his younger brother.
協力してくれるだろうと
思ってな。
だが…。
However...
(ハゴロモ)
兄インドラは それを認めなかった。
Indra did not accept my decision.
そして このときより→
And thus from that day on,
長きにわたる争いが
始まったのだ。
... interminable conflict began.
(ハゴロモ)２人の肉体が滅んでもなお
２人の作り上げたチャクラは→
Even after their flesh perished,
the chakra the two honed
消えることなく
時をおいて転生した。
continued to reincarnate across time,
without vanishing...
over and over.
幾度となくな。
お化けに取り憑かれてるみたいで
なんか やだな。
It kind of sounds like being
haunted by a ghost. It's creepy.
で 今も
誰かに取り憑いてんのか？
So, is it still possessing
someone even now?
お前だ ナルト。
It's you, Naruto.
えっ！
弟のアシュラは お前に転生したのだ。
The younger brother Ashura has
reincarnated as you.
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
boku to yoku ni ta itami uchiake te kure ta hito
Hearing someone tell me about
the same kind of pain I have
futo hitori ja nain datte omoetan da
Made me think that I'm not alone
dakedo nagareta namida kamishime ta nukumori o
But the flowing tears and the warmth I relished
itsumade mo boku wa dakishimete ireru ka na?
How long can those envelop me?
kizutsui te kizutsui te nai te nai te tsuyoku nare subete
Hurting again and again,
crying over and over gives you strength for everything
me ni utsuru sono keshiki wa eien ni tada kokoro e to
That scenery you see goes straight to the heart,
massugu tsunagatte iku
now and forever
hanate niji no sora omoi nara koko ni aru (my heart)
Let it go, the rainbow sky, my wishes are here (My heart)
terase asu wo ima kokoro tsutau messeeji
Shine a light, tomorrow is now,
a message straight to the heart
hanate niji no sora
Let it go, the rainbow sky
If all chakra were to
be reunited into one again,
今日も頑張ります。 皆さんも
盛り上がっていきましょう！
a new Chakra Fruit
would take shape.
That must be prevented
at all costs,
or this world would come
to an end.
I would like you to stop Madara.
In your unpredictability,
I feel the possibility exists.
＜今回は 歌謡界に→
さん然とその名を残す
古賀政男さんのメロディーから→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Sage of Six Paths."
スタートします。
Thanks for believing in us.
まずは 中条きよしさんと→
氷川きよしさんにお願いします＞